本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译
最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译： 潇湘月影 香茗小焙 Reginamoon 鱼小姐  木浅薰
翻译：王大可 真月镜威 小饭 某茶 菲力
时间轴：youliss  倩倩     校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第七集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你咨询中途的时候走掉是因为
You walked out of our session because you didn't want
-你不想谈你的母亲  -你简直疯了
- to talk about your mother. - You're insane.
而你是个自私自利的自恋狂
And you're a self-serving narcissist
为了得到自己想要的东西不择手段
who will do or say anything to get what he wants.
是我妹妹的公司  我会把她这个客户给你
It's my sister's company. I'll give you her business.
而你只需解决她的离婚案
All you have to do is handle her divorce.
好吧
All right, I'll do it.
答应我你不会跟埃斯特睡
Promise me you won't sleep with esther.
我最不想做的事就是和你妹妹睡
The last thing I want to do is sleep with your sister.
今晚你还愿意带我回家吗
Would you like to take me home tonight?
愿意
I would.
弗莱彻成了杰克・索罗夫的客户
Jack Soloff signed Fletcher as a client
而我如今得放弃麦肯诺了
And now I have to let McKernon go.
很抱歉你的尴尬处境
I'm sorry you're in this position right now.
害你陷入这种处境的不是我
I'm not the one who put you in it.
是杰克・索罗夫
Jack Soloff is.
这是你最后一次跟我合作的机会
This is your last chance to work with me.
抓住机会  你还有前途
Take it and you have a future,
抓不住  就去丹尼尔・哈德曼那求职吧
Don't and you can go ask Daniel Hardman for a job.
我准备好谈我母亲了
I'm ready to talk about my mother.
妈妈
Mom?
-妈妈  -哈维
- Mom? - Harvey.
你...你怎么回来了
What are you-- what are you doing here?
学校让我回家
I got sent home from school.
我吐了
I threw up.
那快去躺下吧
Oh, well, let's get you to bed.
莉儿  我在想
Hey, Lil, I was thinking that--
-他是谁  -宝贝  你还记得
- Who's that? - Honey, you remember
我们的  我的堂兄斯考特吗
our cousin-- my cousin Scott?
不记得
No.
你当然记得  他是朱迪叔叔的兄弟
Course you do. He's Cousin Judy's brother.
我不太舒服
I don't feel good.
你发烧了
Oh, yeah, you're burning up.
快去床上躺下
Let's get you to bed.
别告诉爸爸斯考特叔叔的事
And let's not tell Dad about Cousin Scott.
好吗  他们关系不太好
Okay? 'Cause they don't get along.
来吧
Come on.
可怜的孩子
You poor thing.
"可怜的孩子"  我至今难以忘怀
"You poor thing." That's what stuck with me.
她嘴上虽然这么说
She said "You poor thing,"
而事实上她根本一点都不在乎我
but she didn't give a shit about me.
你那时明白自己看见的事吗
And did you know what you saw?
不  我只知道有事情不对
No, I just knew something was wrong.
你没有告诉你父亲
And you didn't tell your father?
她让我别说
She told me not to.
而你相信了她
And you trusted her?
是的
I did.
哈维  我从没想过我会对你说这句话
Harvey, I never thought I'd be saying this to you,
但我很为你骄傲
but I'm proud.
告诉我这些是很需要勇气的
It took an amazing amount of courage to tell me that.
-你不是要和我抱抱吧  -当然不
- We're not gonna hug, are we? - No, we're not.
但真高兴我们终于有了一次
But it does feel good to end a session
圆满结束的咨询
on a positive note for once.
在忙皮特森的案子啊
Peterson case, huh?
我还记得我和那混蛋打交道的时候
I remember when I used to handle that asshole.
有意思  我好像没请你进我办公室
Funny, I don't remember inviting you into my office.
对了  一定是因为
Oh, yeah, that's right, it must be because
那是我绝对不会做的事
it's something that I would never do.
迈克  我知道我阴过你和路易
Listen, Mike, I know I pulled some shit with you and Louis,
但现在我是来与你和解的
but I'm here to make things right with you.
没兴趣
Not interested.
听我说完
Just hear me out.
这是什么东西
What the hell is this?
一个为有冲基金背景的人
It's a case that's tailor-made for someone
量身定做的好案子
with a hedge fund background.
纽约教师的退休基金
New York teacher's pension fund
直接少了三成的年收入
just lost 30% of their annual income.
他们不经对冲就把一半资产投资了衍生品
They put half their portfolio in derivatives without hedging?
不是一般的衍生品  是施特劳斯银行
Not just derivatives. Derivatives created
为了提高收益
and marketed by Strauss Bank
专门创造和经营的衍生品
to increase their own revenue.
抱歉  杰克  我从不与我不信任的人合作
Sorry, Jack, I don't work with people that I don't trust
也从不相信那些连一个好理由都没有
and I don't trust somebody who comes to me saying their trying
就请求和解的人
to make things right without a good reason.
你想要理由  是杰西卡要我这么做的
You want the reason? Jessica told me to.
她没和我说过
Yeah, well, she didn't tell me.
在她说之前
And until she does...
你可以滚出我的办公室了
you can get out of my office.
西蒙案子的简报在你桌上
The Simon brief is on your desk
我把你周三中午的会议移到下午五点了
and I moved your Wednesday noon meeting to five.
为什么
Why'd you do that?
因为安东尼・金博尔在喝酒的时候
Because Anthony Kimball's most honest
最易吐真言
with a drink in him.
除此之外
And on top of that,
我也不希望你在生日这天
I wouldn't want you to have to work too hard
-还辛苦工作  -什么  今天不是我生日
- on your birthday. - What? It's not my birthday.
拜托  你可以和我说的
Oh, come on, you can tell me.
几岁了  48  49
What is it? 48? 49?
-还是六十  -首先  快六十的人可不是我
- The big 6-0? - A: I'm not the one pushing 60.
你最好不是在指我
You better not be talking to me.
其次  就算是  我也一定会找一个
B: if it were, I'd be drinking with someone
比安东尼・金博尔好看得多的酒伴
a lot prettier than Anthony Kimball.
那为什么你日历上的周三晚被
Then why is wednesday night permanently blocked out
永久预定了
on your calendar?
-唐娜  -哈维
- Donna. - Harvey.
-你看上去很忙啊  -因为我确实很忙
- You look busy. - I look busy because I am busy.
忙得都没空和我在周三晚上去戴尔波斯特吃饭了
Too busy to join me at Del Posto on wednesday night?
哈维  我们不用再去了
Harvey, we don't need to do that anymore.
那你为什么
Then why did you leave it
要在我日历上永久预定这一天
permanently blocked off on my calendar?
因为那是我很久以前做的事
Because I did that a long time ago
而我离开时忘记取消了
and when I left your desk I forgot to undo it.
那我们为什么索性当做你是故意
Then why don't we pretend that you forgot
没有取消的呢
to undo it on purpose?
我不再为你工作了
I don't work for you anymore.
还庆祝什么
What would we be celebrating?
虽然不能再庆祝你来为我工作的纪念日
Instead of celebrating the day you came to my desk,
我们来庆祝下
how about we celebrate...
和平共处两周吧
two weeks of being on decent terms?
但刚过了一周半
It's only been a week and a half.
真的吗  唐娜
Seriously, Donna?
我不想只是和平共处
I don't just want to be on decent terms.
我想继续和你当朋友
I want to get back to being friends.
那真的很好  哈维
That's really nice, Harvey.
周三晚上见
See you Wednesday night.
谢谢
Thank you.
杰西卡
Jessica.
看到你真是又惊又喜
What a pleasant surprise.
我们都知道那不是真的
I think we both know that it isn't.
-喜  还是惊  -都不是
- Pleasant? Or a surprise? - Either.
因为我们都知道杰克・索罗夫
Because we also both know that Jack Soloff
在我之前找过你
came to see you before I did.
那有什么问题吗
Is there a problem with that?
如果你试图和我的合伙人
There is if you're colluding
合谋夺取我的律所的话  就有问题
with one of my partners to take over my firm.
杰克来找过我
Jack came to me
向我请教如何搞定一个新客户
asking for advice about how to land a new client.
他的志在必得  让我想到了哈维的
He was so determined I was suddenly reminded
-第一个客户  -麦肯诺汽车公司
- of Harvey's first client. - McKernon Motors.
他那么在意这个客户
A client he cared so much about
以至于可以为了信守承诺
he gave up a promotion
放弃了一次升迁机会
just to keep his word.
这种举动很难让人忘怀
It's hard to forget a move like that.
你企图溜回我律所的种种行为
It's also hard to forget your history
也很难让人忘怀
of worming your way back into my firm.
如果你想给人当导师  丹尼尔
So, if you're looking for someone to mentor, Daniel,
去给课外辅导班上上课吧
go find yourself an afterschool program.
但离我的地盘远点
But stay the hell outta my house.
杰西卡
Jessica...
我对你的烂律所才没兴趣呢
I have no interest in your shitty firm
也用不着我进入你的地盘摧毁它
and I don't have to enter your house to damage it.
在你放弃弗莱彻引擎公司时
You did that all by yourself
就已亲自完成了这个任务
the second you let Fletcher Engines go.
杰克告诉你的吗
Jack tell you that?
弗莱彻引擎公司告诉了所有人
Fletcher Engines told everyone that.
你也告诉你整个律所比起他们
And you told your entire firm that you care more about
你更在乎哈维・斯佩克特
Harvey Specter than you do about them.
失陪了  我有个会
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a meeting
要在我的新办公室开
in my new office.
回到这个城市感觉太好了
It's so nice to be back in the city.
收拾你的东西  滚出我的律所
Clean out your things and get the hell out of my firm.
-什么  -我给了你最后的机会
- What? - I gave you one last chance
而你搞砸了
to play nice, and you blew it.
-我怎么搞砸了  -你是要否认
- How did I blow it? - Oh, you're going to deny
你在公司散播消息
that you've been spreading word around the office
说我让你放弃弗莱彻引擎公司吗
that I told you to drop Fletcher Engines?
是的  我否认  因为我没说过
Yes. I'm gonna deny it, because I didn't do it.
那其他人怎么知道的
Then how the hell does everybody know?
因为我签下弗莱彻的时候告诉他们了
Because I told them when I signed Fletcher.
但如果我知道你会放弃他们
Which I wouldn't have done if I'd known
就不会那么做
you were gonna drop them
因为这让我看起来很惨
Because it made me look like shit.
这也没让我好过
Well, it didn't make me come out smelling like a rose either.
你的导师好像也知道了这事
And your mentor seems to have known that.
他不是我的导师
He's not my mentor.
我去问过他的建议
I went to him for advice,
然后就让我差点被炒掉
and all it got me was almost getting fired.
但你说你会再给我一次机会
But you said you'd give me one more chance,
我也在努力尝试了
and I've been trying to take it.
举个例子
Give me one good example of that.
我今早去找迈克・罗斯合作
I approached Mike Ross to work with me this morning.
顺便提一下  他当场打了我的脸
And by the way, he spat in my face.
杰西卡
Jessica...
你表明了立场  我也听了
You made your point and I heard you.
如果你无论怎样都要解雇我
if you're just gonna fire me anyway,
当初为什么还给我机会呢
why give me the chance in the first place?
开玩笑  你听到我笑了吗
A joke? Uh, do you hear me laughing?
10%已经比你应得的多11%了
10% is 11% more than you deserve.
我
I--
怎么回事
What the hell?
这事最好很重要
This better be important.
我刚要敲定一个交易
I was just about to close a deal.
我听到一个传闻
I just heard a rumor
杰克・索罗夫刚签下了弗莱彻引擎公司
that Jack Soloff signed Fletcher Engines.
不可能  大家都知道如果我们签了麦肯诺
That's ridiculous--everyone knows we can't sign Fletcher
就不能签弗莱彻
if we represent McKernon.
路易  大家知道的是
I'll tell you what everyone knows, Louis.
杰克签了弗莱彻
Jack signed Fletcher.
杰西卡强迫他放弃了他们
Jessica forced him to drop them,
杰克当初能这么做的唯一原因
and the only reason Jack would have done that
就是被麦肯诺解雇了
in the first place is if you were fired by McKernon.
哈维  我可以解释
Harvey, I can explain.
天哪  我就知道
God damn it. I knew it.
等等  哈维  听我说
Just wait a minute. Harvey, listen to me.
杰克陷害了我们
Jack set us up.
他假装很合作
He acted as if he was cooperating
但其实一直在等待机会搞破坏
when all along he was looking to blow up the deal.
那事情发生时你为什么不来找我
Why the hell didn't you come to me when it happened?
因为我们想自己把问题解决
Because we wanted to fix it ourselves.
想自己解决
Wanting to fix it yourself
是你我之间所有问题的原因
is the cause of every problem you and I have ever had,
现在你还把这个狗屁技能教给迈克了
and now you're teaching that bullshit to Mike?
你知道吗  迈克和我一起合作的那个案子
You know what, mike and I worked on that deal together,
我们做的非常完美
and we kicked ass.
我很高兴  迈克也高兴  多米尼克也高兴
I'm happy, Mike's happy, Dominic's happy,
我可以告诉你为什么
and I'll tell you why.
因为我是个非常棒的律师  你也知道这点
Because I'm a damn good attorney, and you know it.
所以如果你来就是为了这件事
So if that's the only thing you came in here for,
我要去完成我的交易了
I would like to close my deal now.
斯佩克特先生  埃斯特・利特刚刚打来电话
Mr. Specter, Esther Litt just called.
她有急事  要马上见你
She has an urgent matter. Needs to see you right away.
她说是什么事了吗
Did she say what it was about?
没说  只说别告诉她哥哥
No. Just not to tell her brother.
原来这里就是小精灵们补充咖啡因的地方啊
Oh, so this is where the little people get their caffeine.
你应该不是来找早餐棒的吧
I'm guessing you're not here to have a breakfast bar.
我这辈子都没吃过早餐棒
I've never had a breakfast bar in my life.
我要谢谢你和杰克・索罗夫一起接手了
I want to thank you for taking on that pension case
-那个养老金案子  -我没有
- with Jack Soloff. - I didn't take on
和杰克・索罗夫一起接手养老金案子
the pension case with Jack Soloff.
-你接了  -杰西卡  别这样
- Yes, you did. - Jessica, no.
你不能逼我和那个人合作
You can't make me work with that man.
只要我想
I can make you work
就算是擦窗工你也得合作
with the goddamn window washers if I want to.
你要是不答应  就等着
And if you don't do this, you might find yourself
挂在外面擦五十层楼的玻璃吧
dangling 50 stories above the ground.
-为什么  -因为我让杰克讲和
- Why? - Because I asked Jack to make peace,
而他选择了你
and you're the one he chose to reach out to,
所以这事得你来干
so you're the one to do this.
我是问为什么不直接炒了他
I guess I meant why don't you just fire him?
要是我炒掉所有
If I fired every ambitious attorney
有野心挤掉我的律师
that ever took me on,
那这个律所里早就只剩我和哈罗德・甘德森了
there'd be nobody left here but me and Harold Gunderson.
等一下  你认识哈罗德・甘德森
Wait a second--you know who Harold Gunderson is?
所有人我都认识
I know who everybody is.
在你接着张口之前
And before you say one more word,
要是哪天我开始给所有找麻烦的人发解聘通知书
if I ever start handing out pink slips for troublemakers,
你绝对是第一个
you'd be the first in line.
好吧
Right.
一收到消息我就赶来了
I came here as soon as I got your message.
一般人可没这待遇
I don't do that for most people.
欲擒故纵的高手啊
So much for hard to get.
我们已经过了那个阶段了吧
I think we're past that.
杰弗里又起贪心了吗
Did Jeffrey get greedy again?
没有  一个名叫肯尼斯・杰克森的人
No. A man named Kenneth Jackson
声称我的无坚果蛋糕
is claiming my nut-free muffins
导致他过敏性休克了
put him in anaphylactic shock.
怎么回事  麦麸放多了
What happened? Too much gluten?
-还是放少了  -哈维
- Not enough gluten? - Harvey,
这不是玩笑  它关乎我公司生存
This isn't funny. This is my company,
我的整个品牌都建立在质量之上
and my entire brand is based on quality.
抱歉  我会认真对待的
I'm sorry. I'll take it seriously.
谢谢你
Thank you.
别谢我  谢路易吧
Don't thank me. Thank Louis.
因为这个案子他来接
Because he's gonna handle this case.
什么
What?
这是公事公办  不是个人决定
This is a business matter, not personal.
我可不会偷走路易的客户
And I'm not stealing Louis's client.
你没偷走我  接手我的离婚案的就是你
You're not stealing me. You already handled my divorce.
你是要告诉我路易比你优秀吗
Are you gonna tell me that Louis is a better lawyer than you?
不  我会告诉你他是个非常棒的律师
No. I'm gonna tell you that he's a damn good lawyer,
而且会不惜一切保护你
and he'd do anything to project you.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
这事得低调解决
I need this to go away quietly,
可路易从来不会低调
and Louis doesn't do anything quietly.
-那你就让他低调  -他从来不听我的
- Then tell him that. - He never listens to me.
那你要么让他听  否则就换家律所吧
Then get him to listen or get another law firm,
因为我是不会接这个案子的
because I'm not taking this case.
哈维  我不需要别的律所
Harvey, I don't need another firm.
我需要你
I need you.
知道我是怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我觉得你是想再跟我约会
I think you want to go out with me again,
然后用这事把我找来
and you came to me with this
因为你不敢跟我直说
because you're afraid to say it to me.
难以置信
I don't believe you!
你觉得我会策划一起针对我自己公司的诉讼
You think I concocted a lawsuit against my own company
就为了告诉一个已经和我在一起的男人
just to tell a man I've already been with
我喜欢他
that I like him?
看起来就是这样
Sure looks that way.
那样的话
In that case,
看来我的确找错了人
I guess I do have the wrong man for the job.
多谢你花时间过来
Thank you for taking the time.
请告诉他我来了
Please let him know I'm here.
埃斯特
Esther.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我昨天说的很清楚了
I thought I was very clear yesterday.
我不会接你的案子
I'm not taking your case.
你的确说得很清楚
You were clear.
我是来找路易的
I'm here to see Louis.
但很高兴见到你还是一如既往的自负
But it's nice to see your ego's as strong as ever.
对不起  昨天我说话太混了
I'm sorry...and I didn't mean to be such a dick yesterday.
没关系  哈维  我懂你的用心
It's okay, Harvey. I know what you did.
你用你口中的罪名指责我
You accused me of what you accused me of,
这样我就会来找路易了
so I will go to Louis.
所以你不生我的气
So you're not mad at me?
其实还有点甜蜜
It was actually sweet...
虽然方法有点混蛋
in a dick-ish sort of way.
那是我的特长
That's my specialty.
谢谢你  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
你好  埃斯特  我是唐娜・鲍尔森
Hi, Esther, I'm Donna Paulsen.
-我是...  -我知道你是谁
- I'm the-- - I know who you are.
你是我哥哥有生以来
You're the best thing
对他最好的恩赐
that's ever happened to my brother.
你知道的还太少
Oh. Well, you don't know the half of it.
但我希望没因为我的紧急通知
Anyway, I hope I didn't put you to too much trouble
-给你带来麻烦  -没有的事
- on short notice. - Oh, nonsense.
路易听说你要来激动死了
Louis was thrilled when he heard you were coming in.
到底是什么重要的事
What was so goddamn important
让我得空出整个上午
that I had to cancel my entire morning?
我发誓他非常乐意
I swear he was happy to do it.
等你要办的事一办完
And you and I are having lunch
我们俩就去吃午饭
the second whatever it is you're here for is over.
-要喝一口吗  -那是李子泥吗
- Want a sip? - Is that a prunie?
不喝  你居然还喝那破玩意儿
No! I can't believe you still drink that crap.
你明知道我和格蒂奶奶一样有结肠痉挛
You know I've got Grandma Gertie's spastic colon.
你到底来干什么
What he hell are you doing here?
有人起诉我
I'm being sued.
天哪
Holy shit.
你那该死的松饼确实让人感染沙门氏菌了
Your shitty muffins really did give someone salmonella.
不是沙门氏菌
It's not salmonella,
还有路易  这事很严肃
and Louis, this is serious.
-事关我的公司  -好吧  抱歉
- It's my company. - All right, I'm sorry.
他这起诉站得住脚吗
Well, does he have a leg to stand on?
当然站不住
Of course not.
每三个月我都会审核一次所有供应商
I do an audit of every supplier every three months.
你确定吗  因为假如我们要
Are you sure? Because if we're gonna
用我们的一切力量反击他的话...
go after him with everything we've got--
路易  我们不会跟他打官司
Louis, we're not going after him at all.
我想要迅速地悄悄地把这事解决了
I want to settle this quickly and quietly.
埃斯特
Esther...
和解的话  你看起来就像是有罪了
You settle, you look guilty.
这是一次敲诈  简单明了
This is a shakedown, pure and simple.
我知道  但我不在乎
I know that, but I don't care.
这是一个商业决策
This is a business decision.
那也是为什么我试图
And that's why I'm trying
阻止别人干同样的事
to stop others from doing the same thing.
我告诉你  我知道自己在做什么
I'm telling you, I know what I'm doing.
我没说你不知道
I didn't say you don't.
是没说  你不过是在对我指手画脚而已
No, you're just telling me how to do my job.
路易  我过来找你是因为你是我哥哥
Louis, I came to you because you're my brother,
我现在就告诉你  这就是我想要的
and I am telling you, this is what I need.
好吧  我们和解
All right, we'll settle.
谢谢你  路易
Thank you, Louis.
不  谢谢你
No, thank you.
为什么
For what?
因为你没去找哈维
For not going to Harvey.
他搞定了你的离婚案
Once he handled your divorce,
我以为你会想要他来处理你的一切事务
I would have thought you'd want him to handle everything.
杰西卡・皮尔逊
执行合伙人
哈维  请别拘束
Harvey, make yourself comfortable.
你要来杯鸡尾酒吗
Can I get you a mimosa?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
我只是顺路过来吃我的早餐百吉饼
I just stopped by to eat my morning bagel
并问问为何杰克・索罗夫
and ask why Jack Soloff
试图签下弗莱彻引擎公司
tried to sign Fletcher Engines
而你却没有告诉我
and you didn't tell me.
我没告诉你是因为我在忙着解决那事
I didn't tell you because I was busy fixing it.
那解决这件事是不是也包括发现他
And did fixing it involve figuring out
去找了丹尼尔・哈德曼
that he went to Daniel Hardman?
事实上  确实如此
As a matter of fact, it did.
你见到了哈德曼
You saw Hardman.
是见到了  也没花多长时间
I did, and it didn't take long,
因为他回到纽约了
because he's back in New York.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
他声称自己和此事毫无关系
He said he had nothing to do with any of this.
没错  他说自己不过是给了杰克一些建议
Yep. He said he was just giving Jack some helpful advice.
我想是时候
Well, I think it's time
轮到我们给杰克一些有用的建议了
we gave Jack some helpful advice of our own,
比如你他妈快另寻高就吧
Like get your ass another job.
哈维  我去找了杰克
Now, Harvey, I met with Jack.
他说他不会再信任哈德曼了
He says he's done confiding in Hardman,
而我也就决定视作此事已了了
and I've decided to consider the matter closed.
你是在告诉我你相信那个小丑吗
You telling me you trust that clown?
也许我看着是很年轻
Now, I may look damn good for my age,
但也不是三岁小孩
but I wasn't born yesterday.
你想知道他和哈德曼到底有多深的牵连
You want to know how deep it goes with him and Hardman,
-是不是  -当然了
- don't you? - I sure as hell do.
这也是为什么我要迈克和杰克合作
Which is why I asked Mike to work with Jack
并且好好相处
and play nice,
而你最好别去挡道
and you better not get in the way.
这看起来可不像是
This doesn't look like
一张"原谅我这么混蛋"道歉卡啊
a "Forgive Me for Being a Dick" card.
本来就不是
It's not.
这是一本给施特劳斯银行的28页的书面质询
It's a 28-page interrogatory for Strauss Bank.
谢了
Thanks.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
你告诉过我你不会和自己不信任的人共事
You told me you don't work with people you don't trust.
我也不会
Neither do I.
你不需要信任我也能明白
You don't have to trust me to understand
施特劳斯银行里的那些龌龊事
that the shady shit at Strauss Bank
是从高层开始的
starts at the top.
牵扯到了最高层吗
All the way to the top?
总裁有一半可能性知情
There's a 50-50 chance that the CEO knows.
而财务总监必须知情
The CFO had tohad to know.
我们只需要搞到他们的电邮就好了
All we have to do is get their emails.
那很容易
That's easy.
只要我们同意不提起刑事诉讼
We agree not to pursue criminal charges,
他们立马就会把邮件交过来了
they'll hand emails over right now.
我们不能放弃威胁要把他们送进监狱
We can't give up the threat of going to prison.
那是我们的筹码  我们必须要打官司
That's what gives us leverage. We have to go to court.
打官司会耗费很长时间的
Going to court will take forever.
我刚刚和罗伯特・赞恩争论过同样的问题
I just went through the same thing with Robert Zane.
你为何不打电话给他
Why don't you pick up the phone
问问他最后谁是对的
and ask him who turned out to be right?
我听说过你很自大
You know, I heard you were cocky,
但真没想到有这么夸张
but I had no idea.
是你来找我讲和的
You're the one who came to me looking to make peace.
你到底还要不要和平共处了
You wanna make peace or not?
好吧  我们试试你的方法
All right. We'll try it your way.
瑞秋  有什么需要我帮助的吗
Rachel, what can I do for you?
我听说了埃斯特的事
I heard about Esther,
希望能帮上点忙
and I was hoping I could help.
谢谢你的好意
I appreciate the offer,
但我打算自己解决这件事
but I'm gonna take care of this one myself.
我不是想要打扰你什么的
And I'm not trying to interfere.
我只是想着假如能向我们这里
I just thought it would be nice to learn
最有才  最勤奋
from the most talented, diligent,
最受人尊重的合伙人学习就好了
and respected partner that we have here.
是啊  你不过是想拍我马屁罢了
Yeah, you're just trying to butter me up.
成功了吗
Is it working?
帅哥
Handsome.
听我说
Listen to me.
她是我妹妹
She's my sister.
有人告了他
She's being sued.
上次她遇到麻烦时  她去向哈维求助
Last time she had a problem, she went to Harvey,
但这次她向我求助了
but this time she's coming to me,
所以我不会让任何人插手这件事的
and I'm not gonna farm any of it out.
你能理解吗
Can you understand that?
我想要参与这个案子的
The reason I want on this case
是因为我崇拜埃斯特和她的公司
is that I admire Esther and her company,
所以假如有人用一个荒唐的官司欺负她的话
And if someone's coming at her with a frivolous lawsuit,
再小的忙我也愿意帮
then...I don't care how little I do.
我只是想帮你
I just want to help you.
文件就在这里
Paperwork's right here.
法官大人  如您所见
Your Honor, as you can see,
这往轻了说是工作疏忽
there's been clear negligence at best,
-往重了说是蓄意行骗  -更不用说
- deliberate deception at worst. - Not to mention
还违反了诚信义务
a breach of fiduciary duty.
我赞同你的观点
I'm inclined to agree.
法官大人  唯一明确的一点
Your Honor, the only thing that's clear
是他的客户选择风险投资
is his clients chose a risky investment.
这可不是欺诈
That's not deception on our part.
他推出这些衍生产品  明知道风险很高
The deception is he created those derivatives,
还是卖给我们  这就是欺诈
he knew how risky they were, and he sold them to us anyway.
我有二十亿投资基金
I have $2 billion in investment funds.
你觉得我每笔投资都会过目吗
You think I review every investment?
不知道  但你绝对看了这笔
I don't know, but you sure as hell reviewed this one.
-证据呢  -目前还没有
- And where's your proof? - We don't have any...yet.
所以我们请求查阅他们的邮件
Which is why we're requesting access to these emails.
这里讨论的不是查阅邮件
This isn't about getting their emails.
而是是否要开庭
This is about determining if trial's moving forward.
结论是要
And it is.
我会在三周后就查阅邮件一事
I'll set the email discovery hearing
-召开听证会  -三周
- for three weeks. - Three weeks?
法官大人
Uh, Your Honor,
我妻子三周后要动手术
my wife has surgery in three weeks.
我申请再延期一个月
I'd like to request an additional month.
还动手术  扯淡呢
Bullshit she has surgery.
预定在哥伦比亚长老教会医学中心剖腹产
Scheduled C-section at Columbia Presbyterian.
那就换个人负责这个案子
Then put someone else on the case.
-事情不是这么干的  -容我说一句
- That's not how it works. - If I may...
如果我们同意不就此进行刑事指控
If we agree not to pursue criminal charges in this matter,
你们会在一周内提供邮件吗
will you give us the emails within the week?
你现在当场同意
You agree to that right here,
我明天就把邮件给你
I'll give 'em to you tomorrow.
一言为定
Then we have a deal.
想告诉我你拿了什么回扣吗
Wanna tell me what kind of kickback you're getting?
-你说什么  -你背着我行事
- Excuse me? - You went behind my back.
我没背着你做任何事
I didn't do anything behind your back.
我是当着你的面做的
I did it in front of your face.
你知道我在说什么  你放弃了我们的筹码
You know what I mean-- you gave up on leverage
给了他一张免罪通行证
by handing him a get out of jail free card,
这说明你要么是他们一伙的
which means you're either in their pocket
要么就是在利用这个案子
or you're using this case
好等事情结束后跟他们签约
so you can sign them once it's over.
-你说什么  -你听得很清楚
- What did you just say to me? - You heard me.
你跟他握手那样子  就像他是你亲戚似的
You shook that guy's hand like you were his goddamn cousin.
听好了  如果他们想做我的客户
You listen to me. If they wanted to be my client,
我会接  但我那么做
I'd take them. But I didn't do that
不是为了拍他马屁
to kiss his ass.
我那么做是为了得到我们需要的东西
I did it to get what we needed.
我们已经有了
We already had what we needed.
不  没有
No, we didn't.
听证会七个礼拜后才召开
We had a hearing on it in seven weeks,
那该死的剖腹产只是冰山一角
and that C-section bullshit was just the tip of the iceberg.
在此期间  他们会想出别的办法
Between now and then, they'd have figured out a way
再把听证会推迟个两年
to put it off for another two years.
-这可未必  -绝对是这样
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
我说过会按你的方法试试  但行不通
I said I would try it your way, and it didn't work.
现在邮件就要来了
Well, now those emails are coming.
你要不要帮我
Are you gonna help me or not?
路易  我得跟你谈谈  有麻烦了
Louis, I need to talk to you--we have a problem.
-什么麻烦  -麻烦是
- What's wrong? - What's wrong
肯尼斯・杰克森的律师
is Kenneth Jackson's lawyer.
她叫莉斯贝・韦克斯勒
Her name's Lisbeth Wexler,
这不是她的第一件恶意诉讼
and this isn't her first frivolous suit.
这些人都是这样
Well, it never is with these people.
这不意味着我们不能和解
That doesn't mean we can't settle.
好吧  你不明白
Okay. You don't understand.
我调查了她经手的数十件案子
I went through dozens of her cases.
每次她拿到开价
Every time she gets an offer,
就威胁说要公之于众
she threatens to go public with it.
-该死  -怎么了
- Shit. - What?
我怕的就是这个
That's exactly what I was afraid of.
好吧  那你该知道  这没什么大不了
Okay, well, then you know it's not a big deal.
我们搞得定  但我们不能开价
We can handle it, but we can't give them an offer.
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.
我告诉过埃斯特可能会发生这种事
I tried to tell Esther this might happen,
可她逼我保证
but then she made me promise
我得不惹麻烦把事情摆平
that I would make this thing go away without any trouble.
好吧  如果我们不做点什么  选择和解
Okay, well, if we don't do something other than settle,
她的麻烦可就大了
she's in for a hell of a lot more trouble.
他没这么说
He didn't really say that.
他不仅这么说了  我还得跟着录音机
Oh, not only did he say it, but I had to transcribe it
逐字逐句抄录下来
word for word off his dictaphone.
-怎么了  -我刚意识到
- What? - No, I just realized
我已经两个小时没有去想
I haven't thought about Jack Soloff
杰克・索罗夫和他的破事了
and his bullshit for two hours.
真高兴我们出来吃饭了  哈维
Glad we did this, Harvey.
我也是  我们应该多出来玩玩
Me, too. We should do it more often.
我不知道米歇尔会怎么想
Well, I'm not sure how Mitchell would feel about that.
米歇尔是谁
Who's Mitchell?
我这六周以来
He's the man that I've been seeing
一直在跟他约会
for the last six weeks.
他...
He's...
他很聪明  风趣
He's smart and he's funny and...
最重要的是  他跟律师行业一点关系都没有
Best of all, he has nothing to do with the practice of law.
我真为你高兴  唐娜
I'm happy for you, Donna.
谢谢
Thanks.
我之所以告诉你
And the reason I told you
是想让你知道我没吃醋
is so that you'll know that I'm not jealous
我想说
when I say...
你得告诉路易
you need to tell Louis
你一直在跟埃斯特上床
you've been sleeping with Esther.
-什么  -得了
- What? - Oh, please.
我今早看到你俩在那里相互对视
It took me all of two seconds to put it together
不出两秒我就想明白了
after I saw you two mooning over each other this morning.
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think.
我处理她的离婚诉讼时  我们相处融洽
We bonded together during her divorce proceedings.
哈维  你说你想跟我做朋友
Harvey, you said you wanted to be friends.
我这么做就是做朋友该做的事
This is me being your friend.
朋友才不会污蔑对方
Friends don't accuse each other of things.
我没有污蔑你  我是想帮你
I'm not accusing you. I'm looking out for you.
这怎么会是帮我
How is that looking out for me?
因为  我说了  你必须告诉他
Because, like I said, you need to tell him.
告诉你  我不用这么做
Well, you know what? I don't need to do that
因为这次  你感觉错了
because, for once, your radar is off.
我没一直跟她上床
We haven't been sleeping together.
我们只睡了一次
We slept together one time.
有什么区别呢
What difference does that make?
你向他承诺了你不会这么做
You promised him you wouldn't do it at all.
唐娜  路易心情好的时候
Donna, Louis isn't rational on his best days
对待与他妹妹无关的事情都不理智
with issues that don't involve his sister,
如果我按你说的做了他会作何反应
Now, how is he going to take it if I do what you're asking?
那你觉得如果被他发现
And how do you think he's gonna react
你做了这事还瞒着他他又会作何反应
when he finds out you kept this from him?
-他不会发现的  -他会的
- He's not gonna find out. - Yes, he is.
是个人都能看得出你俩
Because I didn't have to be me to see the way
对视的时候含情脉脉
you two looked at each other.
总有一天路易也会看出来
And someday Louis is gonna see that, too.
唐娜  我很感激你作为朋友提的建议
Donna, I appreciate you telling me this as a friend.
现在作为朋友  我也告诉你
Now, as a friend, I'm telling you
管好你自己的事就行
to mind your own business.
我说对了  你跟他们做了边线交易
I was right. You cut them some side deal.
你在说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
我看了他们所有的邮件
I went through all their emails
但没有找到任何把柄
and I found them nothing tying them to anything.
也就是说你早知道他们会隐瞒一些邮件
Which means you knew they would leave some emails out
而你利用此事想从中牟利
and you let it go to get something out of it.
我并不知道他们会隐瞒邮件
I didn't know they would leave anything out,
但我确实认为他们会如此
but I thought they might
我也确实打算利用此事
and I am gonna get something out of it,
但并非你想的那样
but it's not what you think.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
你以进监狱威胁他们是对的
Your idea of threatening prison was right,
但从来就没有人曾因为
but nobody ever went to jail
销售劣质证券入狱过
for selling shitty securities.
但可以以销毁证据的罪名起诉他们
They go to jail for destroying evidence.
所以  我没有选择向几位
So, instead of proving to some jury
不懂证券法的陪审团成员
that doesn't understand securities law
解释他们早知道这个投资的风险
that these guys knew the risks of their investments--
只要我们证明他们删除了邮件就行
All we have to do is prove they deleted some emails.
对不起
I'm sorry.
请坐
Take a seat.
这可是你两天来第二次
You know that's the second time in two days
贸然断定我是坏人了
that you jumped right to me being the bad guy?
你得承认  在我和路易
Well, you have to admit, my experience
和你的接触中
with how you treated me and louis
你扮演的就是坏人的角色
was you being the bad guy.
有道理
Fair enough.
但你又知道路易当面骗我说
But were you there when Louis lied to my face
要在一个会议中支持我的事吗
about backing me in a meeting?
你又知道他骗杰西卡
Or when he told Jessica
把他自己干的坏事安在我头上
that I did something awful that he, in fact, did?
我不知道
No, I wasn't.
但你也了解他
But you do know him
你知道他能做出什么事来
and what he's capable of.
但你还是做到了和他和睦相处
And you're somehow on good terms with him.
我能跟他和睦相处
I'm on good terms with him
是因为我见过他好的一面
because I've seen other sides of him.
我也有好的一面
Well, I have other sides, too.
也许我是在律所耍了些龌龊手段
I may have done some office backstabbing,
但我从来没干过什么让你觉得
but I have never done anything to indicate to you
我会犯法的事吧
that I would do something illegal.
而这正是你今天对我的指责
Which is what you came in here accusing me of.
好吧  杰克
Okay, Jack.
我给你一个机会向我展示你好的一面
You can have a chance to show me another side of yourself, too.
我说了让你和解
I told you to settle this thing!
我也想和解啊
And I'm trying to.
那我为什么得到通知说食品及药物管理局
Then why did I just get a notice that the FDA
要调查我的公司
is investigating my company?
-什么  -你干了什么
- What? - What did you do?
我本来是要和解  但瑞秋发现
I was gonna settle, but then Rachel found out
他们的律师经常勒索公司
their lawyer has history of blackmailing companies
所以我只能反诉他了
so our only option was to counter-sue.
你违背了我的明确指示进行了反诉
You filed a counter-suit against my explicit instructions?
埃斯特  是你来找我帮忙
You know what, Esther? You came to me for help,
而我也不会在做松饼的事上对你指手画脚
and I don't tell you how to bake your muffins.
因为你并不了解我的生意的第一要务
Because you don't know the first thing about my business.
而你也不懂我这行的第一要务
And you don't know the first thing about mine.
我不需要懂  我了解你就够了
I don't have to. I know you.
你就是心里埋着满满的
And you've got a chip on your shoulder
自卑感  一旦触发
the size of Montana and when it comes out,
你就会把所有事都搞砸
you make everything worse.
我告诉你  埃斯特
You know what, Esther?
我这么做没有错
I was right to do what I did.
而且这次  我不要接受
And, for once, I'm not gonna let you
你这副居高临下的样子
treat me like I'm less than you.
我对你居高临下
Less than me?
没错  你就是有
Yes, less than you!
我从来都是你的傻哥哥
I'm always your buffoon brother.
这次我决不允许
Well, not this time.
你根本没有权利不跟我商量就这么做
You had no right to do this without asking me!
我不跟你商量是因为你肯定不听我的
I didn't ask you because you wouldn't have listened.
是你从来不听我说话
No, you never listen!
所以我一开始才想去找哈维
Which is why I wanted to go to Harvey in the first place!
-什么  -你没听错
- What? - You heard me.
你怎么可以这样背叛我
How could you betray me like that?
我没有背叛你
I wasn't betraying you.
我只是为自己考虑
I was looking out for myself.
如果你是为了自己考虑
If you were looking out for yourself,
那为什么又骗我说你没去找他
then why did you lie to me about going to him?
因为你一定会嫉妒
Because you're always jealous
只要我去找别人帮忙
whenever I ask anyone else to do anything.
你是我哥哥  路易  不是我男朋友
You're my brother, Louis, not my boyfriend.
你这么想用哈维  你现在就可以去找他
If you wanted Harvey so much, why don't you go to him right now?
我不能
I can't.
因为我去找他的时候
Because when I went to him,
他跟我说我应该信任你
he told me I should trust you.
-他真这么说了  -不仅如此
- He really said that? - He didn't just say that.
他说你是个出色的律师
He said you were a damn good lawyer.
我是个出色的律师
I am a damn good lawyer.
但我确实应该提前告诉你的
But I should have told you.
那么...
Well...
我们现在该怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
那取决于你是不是信任我
That depends on if you think you can trust me or not.
我信任你
I can.
-早上好  路易  -早上好
- Morning, Louis. - Good morning.
你去哪了  我都给你发了八百条短信了
Where the hell were you? I text you like 18 times.
是的  如果真的有紧急情况
Yes, and if it had been an emergency,
我就会给你回电话的
I would have called you back.
那确实是紧急情况
It was an emergency.
路易  曲别针用完了可不叫紧急情况
Louis, running out of paper clips is not an emergency.
我知道  只是我...
I know, it's just that I...
需要你的时候  却找不到你
needed you, and I couldn't reach you,
这种情况从来没发生过
and that's never happened before.
我和哈维吃晚餐去了
I was having dinner with Harvey.
-哈维  -是的
- Harvey? - Yes.
我们希望继续保持朋友关系
We're trying to stay friends.
-朋友  -是的  只是朋友
- Friends? - Yes, friends.
我不会回去为他工作的  路易
I'm not going back to him, Louis.
什么  这我知道
What? I know that.
晚餐怎么样
How'd it go?
还不错
It was fine.
他没有碰巧提起埃斯特吧
He didn't happen to bring up Esther, did he?
什么  为什么要提
What? Why would he do that?
因为很显然  她在来找我之前
Because apparently, she went to him
先去找过他
before she came to me.
是他帮她解决了她的离婚案
Well, he did handle her divorce.
我知道  只是...
I know, it's just...
你觉得他们两个之间
You don't think it's possible that
没发生什么事吧
anything happened between them, do you?
我不知道  路易  我是说...
I don't know, Louis, I mean...
我只知道我们昨晚聊了很多事
Look, I do know that we talked about a lot of things last night,
但并没有提到埃斯特
and Esther wasn't one of them.
你是对的
You're right.
哈维绝对不会答应了我
Harvey would never make a promise like that to me
然后又食言的
and then break it.
我很高兴你晚餐吃得很开心  唐娜
I'm glad you had a nice dinner, Donna.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
他们没有交出来的一摞电子邮件
It's a stack of emails they left out.
你怎么拿到的
How did you get them?
我怎么拿到的并不重要  重要的是我拿到了
Doesn't matter how I got them. It matters that I got them.
这很重要  因为如果你是非法拿到的
It does matter, because if you got them illegally,
那我们就不能用它们  这你是知道的
then we can't use them, and you know it.
我不是非法拿到的
I didn't get them illegally.
那你为什么不告诉我你是从哪拿到的
Then why won't you tell me where you got them?
因为有些事情我不想告诉别人
Because there are some things I like to keep to myself.
而且你不是跟我说什么
And didn't you give me a speech
要了解你的另一面吗
about getting to know different sides of you?
这就是我的另一面
Well, this is a different side of me.
要不要相信由你
Are you gonna trust it or not?
先生们
Gentlemen,
很高兴你们能出席如此仓促的会面
I'm so glad you could see us on such short notice.
你给我们一个面子
Well, you scratched our backs.
我觉得我们也可以还你一个面子
I think we can scratch yours.
你们打算提出什么样的和解方案
What kind of settlement are you looking for?
我们不打算和解
We're not looking for a settlement.
我们希望你能供出你的总裁
We're looking for you to give up your CEO.
-什么  -他不会供出任何人的
- What? - He's not giving anyone up.
你们已经放弃了
You've waived your rights
对这个案子提出刑事指控的权利
to criminal charges in this matter.
对  我们说的不是这个案子
Yeah, we're not talking about this matter.
我们说的是共谋隐瞒证据
We're talking about conspiracy to hide evidence.
这是你的分析师发送的两百封电子邮件
That's 200 e-mails from your analyst
嘲笑你们一起洗劫的那些傻瓜们
laughing about the suckers that you all ripped off.
见鬼
Shit.
别着急  他们肯定不是用合法手段弄到的
Relax. There's no way he got those legally.
-你说得对  这不是合法弄到的  -什么
- You're right, we didn't. - What?
该死  你跟我说...
God damn it, you told me--
我知道我是怎么跟你说的  杰克
I know what I told you, Jack,
但如果我告诉你真相
but you wouldn't have let me come here
你就不会让我来开这个会了
if I told you the truth.
而真相...
And the truth...
是我们还通过非法手段拿到了这封邮件
is that we also got this one illegally.
你的总裁在上面说如果事态变得严重
That's your CEO saying that if push comes to shove,
他就会把你推出来当替罪羊
he's gonna throw you under the bus.
你真的愿意冒险
And you really want to take a chance
赌我们没法合法拿到其它那些电子邮件吗
that we won't figure out a way to find these others legally?
你们公司差不多有两百个人吧
You've got 200 people in your firm?
我们会给每个人提供豁免权以换取他们承认
We're gonna offer every single one of them immunity
这些邮件的存在
to admit they exist.
等他们承认时  你和你的总裁中总有一个人
And when they do, either your CEO is going down,
会为此负责
or you are.
很高兴你们终于清醒过来同意叫我们来和解
Glad you came to your senses and called us to settle.
显然杰克森先生
Well, clearly, Mr. Jackson
已经经受了很多生理上的痛苦
has suffered great physical harm.
我只是希望不会再有人受到伤害
I just don't want anyone else to be hurt.
是啊  那就太可惜了
Yeah, that'd be a shame.
那样你还能告谁去
Then who would you have to sue?
-你说什么  -坐下
- Excuse me? - Sit down.
我们开这个会是因为我妹妹
Now, we're here because my sister
想给你五万来了结这件事
wanted to give you $50,000 to make this thing go away,
但我没有听她的
but I didn't listen to her.
所以现在我自掏腰包再加五万
So I'm gonna throw in an extra $50,000 of my own.
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
因为如果你们以为我们会同意拿十万和解
Because if you think we're gonna settle for $100,000,
那你们这是在浪费我们的时间
you're wasting our time.
十万不是用来和解的
The $100,000 isn't to settle this.
是为了让你的委托人承认
It's to have your client admit that you approached him
他在公共场所发病后你联系了他
after he had a public episode
教唆他宣称自己是在吃了我们的松饼后
and then instructed him to say that it was within five minutes
五分钟内发病的
of eating one of our muffins.
-你没有证据证明这一点  -我们确实没有
- You have no proof of that. - No, we don't.
但他对一个联邦机构所做的虚假陈述
But he's on record for making a false statement
会被记录下来
to a federal agency,
这就意味着等我们真找到证据
which means when we do have proof,
你就要坐很久很久的牢了
you're gonna be in prison for a very, very long time.
十万吗
$100,000?
肯尼斯  等我们打赢官司
Kenneth,You'll get 20 times
你能拿到的钱会是这个的二十倍
that when we win.
或许这能帮你做决定  肯尼斯
Maybe this'll help you decide, Kenneth.
那是什么
What's that?
你使用过这种手段的客户名单
It's a list of all the other people you've done this with.
-什么  -你以为你是她的第一个客户吗
- What? - Oh, did you think you were her first?
你不是
You were not.
排在第一个的能拿到钱
Whoever rolls over first gets the money,
剩下来的只能排队领橙色狱服了
then the rest get to line up for orange jump suits.
够了  我们要走了
That's enough. We're leaving.
我要怎么做
What do I have to do?
埃斯特  你来做什么
Esther, what are you doing here?
我来给你这个
I came to give you this.
这是张十万的支票
This is a $100,000 check.
是给肯尼斯・杰克森的
It's for Kenneth Jackson.
-我们平摊吧  -不要
- We're splitting this. - No, we're not.
你说得对
You were right.
我一开始就不该试图跟他和解
I never should have tried to settle with him in the first place.
你帮我省了不止十万
You saved me more than that.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
说你会原谅我
Say you'll forgive me.
我不觉得你是个傻瓜  路易
I don't think you're a buffoon, Louis,
从来没有
and I never have.
但在亲眼见到之前  我并没意识到
But I didn't realize how good a lawyer you were
你是个如此出色的律师
until I saw it myself.
谢谢你的肯定
I appreciate that.
但我知道你为了生意
But I know how hard you worked
有多么努力
to make your business happen,
我也知道你为此放弃了什么
and I know what you gave up,
所以我绝不会让任何人
and there wasn't a snowball's chance in hell
有丝毫的机会占你便宜
that I was gonna let someone take advantage of you.
谢谢你  路易
Thanks, Louis.
我谢你才对
Thank you.
今晚和我一起吃晚餐吗
Do you wanna get dinner tonight?
今晚不行  明晚如何
I can't tonight. How about tomorrow night?
明晚正好
Tomorrow night is perfect.
我们也邀请唐娜一起如何
What do you say we also invite Donna?
那太棒了
That'd be really nice.
你是过来告诉我今天我表现很棒吗
Come by just to tell me how impressive I was today?
我是过来问你为什么还不信任我
I came by to ask you why you still don't trust me.
谁说我不信任你
Who says I don't trust you?
你没告诉我那份证据是非法得来的
You didn't tell me that evidence was obtained illegally.
杰克  我跟你说的是真话
Jack...I told you the truth.
那些邮件不是非法得来的  因为...
Those emails weren't obtained illegally because...
它们根本不是真的
they weren't even real.
什么
What?
我知道交易员们怎么交流
I know how traders talk.
我很清楚他们会说什么话  所以...
I know exactly what they'd say, so...
那是我自己写的
I just wrote them myself.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you shitting me?
看看吧
Take a look.
我之所以骗你
I lied to you
是因为如果要让他们相信证据是非法的
because to get them to believe they were illegal
就得先让他们相信它是真的
I had to get them to believe they were real.
你需要我发火  帮你增强说服力
And you needed me to be pissed to help you do that.
告诉过你要信任我了
Told you to trust me.
你知道吗
You know what?
我信任你
I do.
跟你说实话
So to tell you the truth,
一开始
when we started this thing,
我只是为了拍你的马屁
I was just doing it to kiss your ass
好让杰西卡原谅我
so Jessica would forgive me.
但是
But...
你是个真正的人才
you're the real deal.
我看到了哈维在你身上看到的品质
I see what Harvey sees in you.
谢谢你  杰克
Thanks, Jack.
或许现在你也可以再给哈维一次机会
Maybe now you can give Harvey a second chance too.
他得到的一切都来得太容易了
It's just everything comes so easy to him.
杰西卡把他从邮件室挑了出来
Jessica plucks him from the mailroom.
史上最年轻的高级合伙人
Youngest senior partner ever.
我努力工作了二十年
I been busting my ass for 20 years.
从来没人为我这样做过
Nobody ever does anything like that for me.
告诉你件事  杰克
Well, I'll tell you something, Jack.
他跟其他所有人一样有自己的烦恼
He's got his own problems just like everyone else.
如果你想跟我友好相处
And if you want to get along with me,
最好也能找到跟他和平共处的方式
you better figure out a way to get along with him.
格蕾琴  卡布里洛索赔案进展到哪了
Gretchen, where were we at with the Cabrillo Claim?
-我得走了  -我不是格蕾琴
- I have to go. - I'm not Gretchen.
这对你来说可不妙
And that's too bad for you,
因为她仍旧习惯帮你遮掩
because she's still in the habit of covering for you.
帮我遮掩什么
Covering for me for what?
我告诉过你路易会发现埃斯特的事
I told you Louis was gonna find out about Esther.
我也告诉过你这跟你没关系
And I told you it's none of your business.
在昨天路易问到我
Well, it became my business
而我为了让他别管这件事
when Louis asked me about it yesterday,
只能当面对他撒谎的时候
and I had to lie to his face
这事就跟我有关系了
just to get him to leave it alone.
我可没要求你那么做
I didn't ask you to do that.
你要求了  你自己心里清楚
Yes, you did, and you know it.
唐娜  我没时间讨论这事
Donna, I don't have time for this.
-我有个约会  -什么约会
- I have an appointment-- - What appointment?
我已经问过格蕾琴了
I checked with Gretchen
所以你别想编个约会借机逃跑
so you couldn't get out of this with some made-up thing.
-你的日程表是空的  -你知道吗  唐娜
- Your calendar's empty. - You know what, Donna?
我历尽艰辛学到的一件事
One thing I learned the hard way
就是不要什么都告诉你的秘书
is not to tell your secretary everything.
小心点  哈维
Be careful, Harvey.
因为你要吃点苦头才能了解
Because you're about to learn the hard way
也许这次我向路易说了谎
that I may have lied to Louis about this once,
但我再也不会这么做了
but I am never, never gonna do it again.
哈维
Harvey?
哈维  这四十分钟你神游去哪了
Harvey, where have you been for the last 40 minutes?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你安排了这次咨询
I mean, you scheduled a session
来跟我谈谈你母亲
so that we could explore your mother,
但你一直在跟我说
and you've been telling me some meaningless story
被蜜蜂蜇的无聊故事
about when you got stung by a bee.
我跟唐娜吵架了
I got in a fight with Donna.
为什么吵架
Fight about what?
她想让我告诉路易我跟他妹妹上床了
She wants me to tell Louis that I slept with his sister.
她希望你这么做的目的何在
Why, exactly, does she want you to do that?
因为我向路易保证过不会那么做
Because I promised Louis that I wouldn't,
她觉得他迟早会发现
and she thinks he's gonna find out.
如果你无意遵守承诺
Why would you make a promise like that to Louis
为什么还向路易保证呢
if you had no intention of keeping it?
我原本一心一意想遵守承诺
I had every intention of keeping it.
那毕竟是路易的妹妹
It's Louis's sister.
但后来我见到她  然后...
But then I met her, and...
该发生的就发生了
It happened.
那你为什么不就这么告诉他
Well, why don't you just tell him that?
因为他就像个四岁小孩
Because he's like a four-year-old,
再说了  她又不属于他
and on top of that, he doesn't own her.
她是他的妹妹
She's his sister.
但这与他和她妹妹的关系无关
But this isn't about his relationship with his sister.
这是他和你的关系
It's about his relationship with you.
你对他承诺了
You made him a promise.
对  只要他没发现我打破承诺
Yeah, and as long as he doesn't find out I broke it,
那就没关系
it doesn't matter.
鉴于你那天告诉我的事
And in light of the story you told me the other day,
这可能也是某个你熟悉的人对她自己说的
that's probably what someone you know very well said to herself.
你放什么狗屁  拿我和她比
Are you shitting me? You're comparing me to her?
没错
I most certainly am.
就好像你把唐娜置于
Right down to you putting Donna in a position
必须隐瞒的处境
not to say anything.
唐娜不是八岁小孩
Donna is not an eight-year-old boy,
我也没有对我老婆劈腿
and I'm not cheating on my wife.
没错  但你让两个你关心的人
No, but you're putting two people you care about
感到被背叛了
in positions to feel betrayed.
-背叛  -没错
- Betrayed? - Yes.
就像某人和另外一个人有了外遇
Like when someone has an affair with someone else.
够了  你没资格这么对我说话
Okay--you don't get to say that to me.
我的工作就是这么对你说话
It's my job to say things like that to you.
那你就是胡说八道
Then you don't know what you're talking about,
因为我整个人生就是不去
because I've lived my whole life
-重蹈她的覆辙  -当一个人那么做
- not to be her. - And when people do that,
常常会以另一种方式成为了那样的人
they very often become that very thing in a different way.
我才不是她呢
Well, I'm not goddamn her!
好吧  那你最好照照镜子
Well, then, you better take a look in the mirror.
因为你许下承诺又偷偷背着别人
Because you made a promise, snuck behind someone's back
打破承诺  当要面对事实时
to break it, and when confronted with that fact,
你就推脱掉所有责任
you're denying all responsibility.
在我看来  这就像是外遇
That sounds like an affair to me.
你找我吗
You wanted to see me?
你知道我多努力才走到今天这一步
Do you know how hard I worked to get a view like this?
瓦萨学院全额奖学金
Full scholarship to Vassar.
三年哈佛法学院
Three years Harvard law,
作为第三巡回法庭的首位黑人女性
and one year as the first black woman
做了一年的书记员
to clerk in the third circuit.
我不会轻易让别人夺走
And I'm not going to waste all that hard work
我辛辛苦苦争取到的一切
just to let someone take everything away.
杰西卡  在我看来
Jessica, as far as I can tell,
杰克・索罗夫遵守了他的承诺
Jack Soloff is holding up his end of the bargain.
不只这样  他还发了一封邮件
He's doing more than that. He just sent out an email
提名你作为初级合伙人
nominating you for junior partner.
你得想办法拒绝
And you're gonna figure out a way to turn it down.
-什么  -没事  消化一下
- What? - Go ahead, take a minute.
恭喜你  你应得的
Congratulations. You've earned it.
你是我见过最优秀的助理律师
You are the best associate I have ever seen.
现在你有如下选择
Now, these are your options.
医疗事故  家庭问题
Medical issues. Family emergency.
你还没有准备好
You're just not ready.
无论如何  这一次你就是不能接受
Whatever it is, you simply cannot accept
初级合伙人这个职位
a junior partnership at this time.
杰西卡  没有人会拒绝当合伙人
Jessica, no one turns down partner.
现在有了
Well, they do now.
因为我不会发一篇通讯稿
Because I'm not sending out a press release
宣布哈佛毕业的迈克・罗斯升职了
announcing Mike Ross of Harvard just got promoted.
-那就不要发稿  -你没听我说的话
- Then don't send one out. - You're not hearing me.
不  是你没在听我说话
No, you're not hearing me.
如果有消息传出去
What do you think is gonna happen
我得到了每个助理律师梦寐以求的职位
when word gets out that I was offered the one thing
却拒绝了  你觉得之后会发生什么事
that every associate dreams of, and I turned it down?
没什么事会发生
Nothing's going to happen.
因为你要绞尽脑汁
Because you're going to put your mind
像当初你无比热忱地糊弄到这个职位那样
to finding a good reason with as much enthusiasm as you did
去找一个好理由
bullshitting your way into this job
来回绝这个提议
in the first place.
-这是什么  -你明知故问
- What is this? - You know what it is.
我希望你替我给
Portfolio of business I want you to take
皮尔逊-斯佩克特的案子
to Pearson Specter for me.
我不会那么做的
I'm not doing it.
这是你的机会  杰克
This is an opportunity for you, Jack.
不  丹尼尔  这对你来说是机会
No, Daniel, it's an opportunity for you,
我没兴趣再替你趟浑水了
and I'm not interested in carrying your water.
是我记错了  还是我们没讨论过这事
Am I mistaken, or did we not have this discussion?
我们以前讨论过...一次
We discussed it...Once.
我记得
I remember.
那次是你跑来找我
It was during that same conversation we had
讨教如何在背后
when you came to me for advice on the best way
捅哈维刀子
to stab Harvey in the back.
受教了  你帮了我一个忙
I get it. You did me a favor.
但我罢手了
But I'm finished.
我不需要你的建议或者捷径了
I don't want your advice or your shortcuts anymore,
因为那差点害我被解雇
because all it did was almost get me fired.
所以请你...拿着这个
So please... Just take this.
你总是这么兢兢业业  杰克
Ah, you've always been a grinder, Jack.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我很欣赏
I admire it.
但你不只是那种书呆子律师
But you're not just a grinder.
你是一个不安分的人
You have a chip on your shoulder.
有件事我清楚
And the thing I've noticed
像你这样不安分的人
about people with chips on their shoulder
总有一天
is that somewhere along the way
会想方设法找别人的茬
they went to great lengths to get 'em off.
我已经找过茬了
I got the chip off my shoulder.
我得到了杰西卡的尊重
I got Jessica's respect.
她并不尊重你
She doesn't respect you.
而且我指的也不是那件事
And that's not the chip I'm talking about.
别再打给我了
Don't call me again.
埃斯特  你在这里做什么
Esther, what are you doing here?
我其实是来和路易唐娜吃晚餐的
I'm actually going out to dinner with Louis and Donna.
感谢邀请
Well, thanks for the invitation,
但我现在最不想做的就是这件事
but that's the last thing in the world I want to do right now.
我来这里不是为了这个
That's not why I'm here.
我在考虑你说的
I was thinking about what you said
我为什么先给你打电话
about why I called you first
而你是怎么看的
and then about how you handled it.
我想...
And I thought...
也许你这周可以约我出去
maybe you might want to take me out this weekend.
埃斯特  你觉得我们是什么关系呢
Esther, what do you think's going on between us?
-我不知道  我只是...  -你不知道吗
- I don't know, I just-- - You don't know?
那我告诉你  我们曾共度良宵
Well, I'll tell you. We had a moment.
很美好  但我无意再偷偷摸摸下去了
It was nice, but I'm not interested in sneaking around.
谁说什么偷偷摸摸了吗
Who said anything about sneaking around?
我说的  你才刚离婚
I did. And you just got divorced.
你是两个孩子的母亲
And you're a mother of two,
我不想导致...
and I'm not gonna be the reason that--
-导致什么  -没什么
- That what? - That nothing.
你为什么不出去吃晚饭
Why don't you just go out to your dinner?
哈维  告诉我这是什么情况
Harvey, tell me what's going on.
情况就是  你请我去吃饭被我拒绝了
What's going on is, you asked me out and I said no,
所以请你别再吵我了
so please just leave me alone.
哈维
Harvey--
我说别吵我了
I said leave me alone.
你在莎拉贝思餐厅订座了吗
Did you make the reservation at Sarabeth's?
你都问第七次了  订了
For the seventh time, yes.
这餐厅为什么重要到非得去那里
And why was it so important that it be there anyway?
因为他们做的松饼比埃斯特的好吃十倍
Because their muffins are ten times better than Esther's,
我想让她知道
and I just want her to know it.
我以为你俩关系改善了
I thought you two made progress.
她依然是我姐姐啊
She's still my sister.
我不能让她以为她在一些事情上是最厉害的
And I can't let her think that she's the best at something.
好吧
Okay.
等等  出什么事了吗  你很沮丧的样子
Wait--what's wrong? You look upset.
没什么事  我只是不太舒服
Nothing's wrong. I'm just not feeling very well.
看来今晚似乎不太合适
It looks like tonight's not a good night after all.
不不不  你很沮丧
No, no, no, you're upset.
不是那样的  路易
It's not that, louis.
我就是不太舒服
I just don't feel well.
拜托  改天再约吧
Please, let's just reschedule.
我给餐厅打电话  然后
I'm gonna just call the restaurant and--
等一下  等一下
Wait a second, wait a second, wait a second.
她跑这么老远  就为了取消约会吗
She came all the way down here just to cancel?
我不知道  路易  可能是她
I don't know, Louis, I mean, maybe she was
已经往这里来了  然后...
already on her way over here and--
她是从哈维的办公室过来的吗
Did she just come from Harvey's office?
因为她是从那里过来的
Because that's the direction she came from,
不是从电梯那里
Not the elevators.
我不知道  路易  你想让我说什么
I don't know, Louis. What do you want me to say?
"我不知道"
"I don't know"
我之前问你
is exactly what you said
哈维和埃斯特之间
when I asked you if you thought
有没有发生什么时  你就是这么回答的
there was anything going on between Harvey and Esther,
现在你又这么说
and now you're saying it again.
但你是唐娜  你什么都知道
But you're Donna, and you know everything.
抱歉  路易  我确实知道
I'm sorry, Louis. I do know.
-你要干什么  -跟你没关系
- What are you gonna do? - None of your business.
别管了  你已经做得够多的了
Stay out of it. You've done enough.
你和我现在得谈谈
You and I are gonna have a talk right now.
无论是什么  都等一下
Hey, whatever it is... it can wait.
我得告诉你一件事
I need to tell you something.
跟我姐姐很沮丧地离开这里
Does it have something to do with why my sister
都不去吃晚饭有关吗
just left here too upset to go out to dinner?
你个混蛋  我就知道
You piece of shit. I knew it.
你对她做了什么
What'd you do to her now?
我没对她做什么  路易
I didn't do anything to her, Louis.
我说现在
And when I say now,
指的是相对于你跟她睡过的以前
I mean as opposed to before when you slept with her.
没错  是唐娜  就是前几天晚上你从我这里偷走
That's right--Donna, the one you tried to steal from me
拉去吃晚饭的人告诉我
at dinner the other night told me--
冷静点  我没想偷任何...
Calm down, I didn't try to steal any--
你向我保证过的
You made a promise to me!
即便我告诉过你
And even after I told you
埃斯特和我小时候
about when Esther and I were kids
男孩子们都利用我接近她
and the boys used me to get to her,
你依然义无反顾地背叛我
you still went ahead and betrayed me.
路易  已经发生了
Louis, it had already happened,
我正要告诉你
and I was just now about to tell you.
瞎说  你根本没打算要告诉我
Bullshit! You were never gonna tell me.
你打算把这个秘密
You were gonna keep it to yourself
-带进棺材里  -路易  你必须相信我
- till the day you died. - Louis, you have to believe me.
我发誓我正要去告诉你
I swear I was just about to tell you.
你要做的是准备好被暴揍一顿
What you're about to do is get your ass kicked.
好吧  你小心点
All right, watch yourself.
别威胁你对付不了的人
Don't threaten something you can't handle.
你觉得我对付不了你吗
You don't think I can handle you?
你还以为我会蠢到发现不了呢
You also thought I was too stupid to find out,
但我发现了
but I did find out.
我发现你不过是个撒谎...
I found out that you're nothing but a lying, cheating--
我没有欺骗埃斯特
I did not cheat with Esther.
那是两个成年人
It was two grown people
自己做出的一个决定
making a goddamn decision for themselves.
那个决定却以
Well, that decision ended
她哭着走出这里结束
with her walking out of here near tears
因为她不清楚全部真相
because she didn't have all the facts,
比如你是个玩弄女人的惯犯
like the fact that you're a serial womanizer
别的女人一撩拨
who can't stand when anyone else
-就不能自持  -快闭嘴
- has anything. - Shut the hell up!
所以能到手的女人他都要
So he takes whatever woman's in sight...
-我告诉你  -因为他在可怜的童年时期
- I'm telling you. - Because he's so messed up
遭受了什么破事  导致他现在
from whatever goddamn thing happened to him
-这么人渣...  -闭嘴
- in his pathetic childhood... - Shut the hell up!
他不能
He can't--
哈维
Harvey.
滚开
Get away from me.
你滚出去
You get the hell out of here.